Contact

9802921405 (Work) sadenichole@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/sadenichole (LinkedIn)

goglobalwithsade.com (Company)

Top Skills

Nursing
Patient Safety
Healthcare

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

Publications

Teaching-Learning Strategies to Improve Critical Thinking in Nursing Students: Development of Critical Thinking Skills to Enhance Patient Care

Sade Nichole

PRN Nurse at The Moses H. Cone Memorial Hospital

Raleigh-Durham, North Carolina Area

Summary

Dedicated, compassionate, highly motivated nurse possessing experience in bedside and clinical care, my training has equipped me with the necessary tools to promote any healthcare system's image. With developed organizational and tactile skills and the ability to take initiative and to give patients a proactive and responsive service, I am able to deliver effective health care. My ability to be empathetic, caring, an effective communicator, and an advocate for my patients is the strength of my leadership. Continuing to further my education and devotion to life-long learning will allow me to keep abreast of the ever changing world of healthcare. Supervisory and more than 4 years of customer service experience is an addition to what I can bring to any vicinity.

Experience

The Moses H. Cone Memorial Hospital PRN Nurse
March 2020 - Present (4 months)
Greensboro, North Carolina, United States

Platinum Healthcare Staffing, Inc. PRN Nurse October 2019 - Present (9 months)

PlanNet Marketing Travel
Marketing Representative
September 2017 - March 2020 (2 years 7 months)

InteleTravel.com
Independent Travel Agent
September 2017 - March 2020 (2 years 7 months)

NurseChoice Travel Nurse October 2018 - August 2019 (11 months)

MGA Healthcare
Travel Registered Nurse
May 2018 - September 2018 (5 months)
California

Platinum Healthcare Staffing, Inc. Travel Nurse October 2017 - April 2018 (7 months) California

LiquidAgents Healthcare
Travel Nurse
July 2016 - October 2017 (1 year 4 months)
Columbia, South Carolina

KPG Healthcare, LLC.
Travel Nurse
April 2016 - July 2016 (4 months)

Westways Staffing Services, Inc Travel Nurse April 2016 - July 2016 (4 months)

Cross Country TravCorps
Travel Nurse
April 2014 - April 2016 (2 years 1 month)
TRAVEL ASSIGMENTS

° 11/15- Present: Med Surg RN, University of California Irvine Medical Center, Orange, CA

07/15-10/15 Float RN Med-Surg/Telemetry, Intermediate Care Unit,
 Emergency Dpt. Inpatient, Ortho/Neuro Trauma Unit, Cardiovascular Center-University of California San Diego-San Diego, CA-Level 1 Trauma Center,
 582 bed hospital in the Hillcrest area (1 of 2 campus's), Epic charting system.
 Magnet Recognized

- 02/15-06/15-Transport RN Med-Surg/Telemetry-University of California/Irvine Medical Center-Orange, CA-Level 1 Trauma Center, 449 bed hospital, Quest charting system. Magnet Recognized
- 04/14-12/14- Nurse Coordinator for the Center for Liver & Disease
 Transplantation-Cedars Sinai Medical Center-Los Angeles, CA-Level 1
 Trauma Center, 958 bed hospital, Epic charting system. Magnet Recognized

US Navy

Registered Nurse

January 2012 - April 2014 (2 years 4 months)

Naval Hospital Camp Lejeune-Camp Lejeune, NC-Primary Casuality Trauma Center, 236 bed hospital, Essentris charting system

Postpartum Mother-Baby 1 year 2mos Medical-Surgical 1 year 2mos Float RN to ICU

- •Formulated and implemented a plan of care for each patient
- Collect, document and evaluate patient data
- •Administered medications, IV therapy and performs special tests and procedures
- •Institute the delivery of emergency measures and performs other duties as assigned
- Managerial responsibilities include charge nurse, supervisor and leader for
- 1-2 Naval Officers, 1-4 Enlisted personnel, and 2-3 Civilian nurses per shift
- •Maintained responsibility for self-development by reviewing current nursing literature and research and continuing education
- •Served as preceptor to train newly hired nurses and military personnel

Duke University Health System
Registered Nurse
September 2011 - March 2012 (7 months)
Durham, NC

Cardiothoracic Surgery Stepdown Unit-Level 1 Trauma Center, 938 acute care bed hospital, Epic charting system

- •Formulate and implement a plan of nursing care for each patient
- •Collect, document and evaluate patient data

- •Administer medications, IV therapy and performed special tests and procedures
- •Institute the delivery of emergency measures and performed other duties as assigned
- •Overlook telemetry systems that required ECG interpretation certification
- •Maintain chest tubes, pacemakers, PICC lines and other drainage systems appropriate for cardiac and thoracic surgical procedures

Sunrise Senior Living

2 years 2 months

Wellness nurse

October 2010 - February 2011 (5 months)

raleigh-durham, north carolina area

- •Ensured the overall well-being of residents with Alzheimer's/Dementia
- •Responsible for the primary care and coordination of health care services for 117 residents with Alzheimer's/Dementia
- •Communicated with resident support services and families, maintained clinical quality assurance while leading and demonstrating the mission and purpose of the facility
- •Managed and supervised 15-20 nursing assistants
- Assisted in training and monitoring of medication administration by nurse assistants
- •Developed monthly care plans for continuous care for 117 residents

Care Manager

January 2009 - October 2010 (1 year 10 months)

- •Provided assistance to residents with tasks involving grooming and personal hygiene
- •Assisted with daily activities of living including light housekeeping, providing dining services, laundry, attended and promoted social events while maintaining patient safety
- Leader of various group activities
- •Monitored and took action on changes in residents health condition and recommended adjustments in level of care and services
- •Interacted and communicated with families providing them with health status updates

Education

Walden University

Doctor of Nursing Practice · (2018 - 2020)

Norwich University

Master of Science (M.S.), Nursing Education · (2013 - 2015)

North Carolina Central University
Bachelor of Science (BS), Registered Nursing/Registered
Nurse · (2006 - 2010)